Hello, I am Deepali Rana, you are watching
Your Money, your favourite show which
helps you in improving your financials,
helps in your future planning,
so if you also want to come to Your Money,
want to ask any question related to your investment, want to understand how to
make a strategy, how to create a portfolio to
achieve your goals, then
write your questions to us.
You
can connect with CBC Awas through WhatsApp, email or Facebook, Twitter
in this show of Your Money. Our email is Your
Money
WhatsApp number is 70452000.
You can also watch this show live on Facebook and Twitter.
You can also post your questions to us by writing #g ask awaaz your
money.  Today we have with us
Pankaj Matpal, MD of Optiv Money Managers.
Hello Pankaj ji, you are welcome and Pankaj
ji, we
usually talk about portfolio creation and improving the portfolio in the show.
But
before starting financial planning, one very
important aspect is insurance.   Be
it life insurance or
health insurance.  And health and
insurance is a subject that is still
under-penetrated.  A
considerable percentage of people do not know its relevance.  So
today in the show, first of all we will discuss
why health insurance is necessary
?  How can we plan our health insurance
before starting any investment?  So
tell me.
Hello Diwali.  You are absolutely right.
See, we invest so that we can
achieve our financial goals.  But if we have
not taken health insurance and if the
need arises to get admitted in the hospital
and it is often seen that at some point in life a
person or someone in the family
needs to go to the hospital.
So in such a situation, the money that you are
saving and investing
for future financial goals will face problems
because that money may be spent in the hospital.
So, if you are
paying a small premium for health insurance, you have the peace of mind that
you have insurance and will be
covered if needed.  And secondly,
if the need really arises then
you will get financial support in that case.  For this,
before starting financial planning,
insurance and that too health insurance is necessary
because when we talk about term
insurance or life insurance, its
purpose is that if the
earning member of the family has
dependent family members on him, then it will be
needed.  But health insurance is such a
thing that there should be cover for oneself as well as for the family members
so that if such a
situation arises and if needed, financial
assistance can be provided.   Yes.
But there is one more thing.
Generally, when health insurance is talked about
, people look at it from the perspective
that you need it more in older age.
So instead of taking it now, you should take it a little later.  Right now
because there is a tendency that
less people think about using it, so I would
like to understand from you when should one take
health insurance, how much, the sooner one takes it, will it be better or should one wait, what should be the ideal strategy, Deepali you are right, people think that more diseases can occur as the age increases, but this is not true, yes if we
talk about lifestyle diseases, then it is true that
hypertension, diabetes, although nowadays
I have seen that
even at the age of 30-30 years, many people complain of diabetes and
hypertension.  But still,
this complaint may be less in children.
But this does not mean that other
diseases cannot occur.  So,
in health insurance, the child can get cover only after he is 90 days old.
So, if the child
is a brand new born baby, then parents should include
him in their policy as soon as he becomes eligible after 90 days.   That is to
say, you should
get cover as soon as you can.  Because
diseases do not occur only in the form of lifestyle diseases.  There are
many elements
, many diseases that can happen to anyone at
any time and one may have to be admitted to the hospital.
Yes, it is true
that as I said, as
soon as the child turns 90 days old,
he becomes eligible
for health insurance and he must take it.
But if you are talking about when your age
increases then you should also have other insurance policies
like health insurance.
Critical illness cover
covers serious illnesses like hypertension, kidney transplant,
and where a large cover is required, one should
consider adding that too.  But the basic mediclaim
policy, the basic health insurance
policy, is better to take as soon as possible.
Okay Pankaj ji, one more thing, the
base of health insurance has
expanded a lot today.  Now you
get a lot of options.  You need complete family coverage
, individual coverage.  So we will
understand two things from you here.  First of all,
how many types of health insurance
are available and if someone is buying health
insurance, what things should be kept in mind, are there any
dos and don'ts?
Look Deepali, the first thing is that what
we just talked about is that a person is admitted in the hospital for a
minimum of 24 hours. If a person is
admitted and he has insurance cover,
in that case his expenses are reimbursed.
So this is a basic health
insurance plan.  Here you
can take individual plan as well as floater plan.  What happens
in a floater plan is
that more than one
family member can be covered under a single policy.  So husband,
wife and children up to 25 years can be
covered in a single policy.  The benefit of this is
that a policy of Rs 5 lakh has been taken.  For
example, cover up to Rs 5 lakh
is available.  Whether it is used entirely by one person
or by more than one person throughout the
year.  So this is the basic thing, one should
take a hostelization cover
but along with that, as I
mentioned earlier, one should also take a critical illness policy
because in case of any serious disease, be it cancer
or along with
cancer like diabetes or
hypertension, heart attack etc., the
expenses are high in such serious diseases.  If you have a kidney transplant,
you should
also take a separate critical illness cover for it.  Especially when there is a
family history, then
its need is felt more.  Apart from that, nowadays there
is a super top-up plan.  Like I said,
we are talking about basic cover that you have
taken a cover of Rs 5 lakh or Rs 10 lakh.  But because of the way the
expenses have increased in today's date, this much cover is available.  Medical expenses have
increased a lot.  So you should think
about taking health insurance of Rs 50 lakh or even Rs 1 crore.
And for this you have the option of
Super Topup Plan.  In Super Top Up
Plan or Top Up Plan,
basically what happens is that if you have
taken a basic cover of Rs 10 lakh, then if the
cover comes for Rs 10 lakh, then you will take the cover from the basic policy
and the amount above that,
you will claim it from the Super Top Up Plan.
So, the premium of super top-up plans is
very low
because here it is known that the
small cover will not be claimed.  He will
come there only when he grows up.  So the premiums for this are
low.  So in this way, if you take a
basic cover and also a super top up plan, then
your cover will increase.
This should also be thought about.
Apart from that, there are many add-on
benefits like OPD cover or
pregnancy cover or daily cash
benefit. When a person is admitted in the hospital,
daily cash benefit
is also available for the additional expenses incurred at that time.  Apart from that, there is a personal accident
policy which can also be covered.  So it can be
taken as an add-on policy or as a separate stand-alone policy.  But the
beginning should be from your mediclaim
policy which we know as basic
mediclaim policy or basic health
insurance policy.   Okay, let's
go and anyway, health insurance
is such a topic that the more it is discussed,
the better it can be and this entire show can easily be
discussed.  But
Pankaj ji told you the main points.  It
is very important to take health insurance.   Should be
taken at an early age.  Be it senior citizens
or family floater policies, you
can take them and you definitely get tax benefits.
If you are taking a policy for a senior citizen,
you get a benefit of Rs 500
and if you are taking it as an individual, you get a benefit of up to Rs 25,000.
Before taking the question, you can quickly see the top four
health insurance plans on your screen.
This has been suggested by Pankaj ji.
If you have not taken health insurance yet,
then you can go with any one of these four
plans.  And multiple
aspects have already been explained to you.  How does
this work?  Is.  How you
can also increase the insurance amount going forward.
And if you have any other questions
related to health insurance, feel free to
send us your questions.  At Your Money, we will
try our best to address them.
Talk to the caller.  Sandeep is with us
from Pune.  Sandeep, tell me hello.
What is your question?
Hello Deepali ji.
hello.
Yes my existing portfolio is HDFC
top 100 ₹000
we are ok.  ICICI
Prove Blue Chip Equity ₹4500
Small Cap ₹2000
ABCL 96 Tax Lead ₹2000 Total My
SIP is ₹1500
My total corpus till now is ₹1 lakh.
So my target for next 15 years is ₹1 crore.
Is there any changes in my
portfolio?  And what is the value of your portfolio right now,
Sandeep?
13 Take.
Ok.  13 Take.  Ok.  So, that means you have done a decent
accumulation till now.  And
Pankaj ji quickly has a small portfolio.
He has not done a single clutter.
He told you that the names of the funds are
also on the screen.  Total SIP of Rs 10,500,
his current portfolio value is Rs 13 crore 13 lakh
and his target is Rs 1 crore
in 15 years.  So your suggestions on his goals and his
portfolio.
Absolutely see, you are investing Rs
10,500 and along with that you
already have a corpus of Rs 13 lakh.  So with this
you can definitely achieve this.   There does
n't seem to be any problem there.
And if I am assuming, it means a
CAGR of 12% here because
returns in mutual funds are not guaranteed.
But in the long term, if you have an equity
portfolio, you can
assume a compounding compounded annual growth rate of 12%.  According to
that,
you can definitely achieve your goal here in 15 years.
As far as schemes are concerned, I would
suggest you some changes.
For example, if you have HDFC Top 100
because you have two schemes in large cap and
two schemes in small cap,
then I would say that you should exit from HDFC
Top 100 fund and HSBC Small Cap
Fund and in its place,
if you add Canara Rubic Flexi Cap Fund
and Motilal Oswal Mid Cap Fund, then
it would be better.  So
I am advising you to exit two funds and
add two new funds
so that your portfolio becomes one with
equity but well diversified.
We say
ok, so you can exit two funds
which include HDFC Top 100 HSBC Small Cap, in
their place you can add Motilal Loswal Mid Cap and
Can Book Flexiap.  As far as
your goal is concerned, in 15 years you will be able to easily accumulate
not just Rs 1 crore but around Rs 1 crore.
Maybe even more than that.  Let's
talk to the next caller.  Sachin is with us now
from Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh.  Hello Sachin,
tell me your question.
Yes ma'am good evening.  I am Sachin speaking
from Jabalpur.
Tell me what is your question?
Yes ma'am, I am 35 years old.  I will
retire at the age of 60, ma'am.  So I still have 25
years.  I am in central government job.
Ma'am I have some mutual funds pay schemes.  There is
large cap, there is Parag Pari's flex
, there is small cap, there is mid cap.  And ma'am,
I get ₹31,000 deducted
from my account every month.
I also have NPS ma'am.
Ok.
Ok.  So how long have you been investing in this mutual fund
?
ma'am?  I have just started.  Please understand that it has been
only two-three months, ma'am.
Ok.  So, that means you have recently made
accumulation and they have a
combination of traditional plus aggressive portfolio.
Pankaj ji, first let me tell you about SIP of
their mutual funds, in that there is Add
Wise Balance Advantage Fund of ₹1000 per month.   ₹1500
in crob small cap ₹1500 in IC Pro Value
Discovery ₹1500 in Parag Parik Flexi
Cap and ₹2500 in Quant Larger Mid Cap ₹
2500 per month and ₹6000 per month in Quant Tax Plan.
This is about the mutual fund
portfolio which is worth Rs 15,000.
They are investing Rs 16,000 monthly in NPS,
PPF and Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana, which
totals around Rs 16,000.  His goal is to earn Rs 10
crore in 25 years because he is
planning to retire at the age of 60.  There
is also a plan to increase SIP by 10% every year.  What is your view on their strategy,
their portfolio and their goals?
See the amount is fine.  If you are
investing ₹31,000 and
can increase it by 10%, then definitely
in such a long term, if the view is of 25 years, then you can become ₹1
crore.  But there will have to be some changes in the
investment strategy.
Now, in NPS, you are
saying that you want to invest a huge amount of Rs 31,000 in NPS.
So
NPS is a market linked product
and you are also investing in mutual funds.
Moreover, there
is more flexibility in mutual funds.  So if you want to do it
as per tax saving because
you get additional tax benefit on annual contribution up to ₹00.
So
you should definitely do that accordingly.  But it is
not necessary to invest much here.
So even if you spend Rs 5000 per month there,
according to me that will be enough.   It becomes
60000.  With that,
instead of investing the money that you save in NPS,
you should add it to mutual funds
and also because
you are contributing to Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana as well
but the
target you have taken there is very small,
₹1000 per month, so my opinion would be
that you should increase the amount there
and apart from that, whatever existing
schemes you have in mutual funds like
Parag Parikh Flexi Cap Fund, Rubeco
Small Cap Fund and ICI Potential
Value Discovery Fund, you should add that amount in these funds,
then your
SIP amount which is very less in these schemes will
increase a bit and your investment in NPS
as I said should be ₹5000 per month
only and here also there is PPF, whatever
target you have taken, stick to it, there is
no problem.  If you are planning to earn ₹1000 per month, then with this
target of 25 years, you
can definitely achieve your goal.
We are fine.  So there
is a need to change the investment strategy a bit.  Invest
just ₹5,000 in NPS.  Invest the remaining money
in mutual funds and with this investment
you will be able to achieve your goal easily in 25 years.
Let's stop
with this for a break.  I'll
take a few more questions after the break.  Pankaj ji is still with us.
You keep watching your money.
You are watching your money.  Pankaj
Mathwal is present with us.  And now let's take
some more questions.  S K Singh is present with us.
Hello Mr Singh.  Tell me what is the question?
Hello ma'am.  I wanted to know that
I have a fund of PSM Axis
Long Term Equity Fund in which I am depositing
₹1000 through FRP
continuously since December 2014.  And right now
I have it,
right?
Its corpus has reached around Rs 2 lakh.
But at this time his growth is quite good.
He is not doing well.  The reason
I wanted to ask was whether it would be okay to continue in it
or not?  Or should I replace it with some
other fund which will give me
growth in the coming years.
Ok?  So the question is about Axis Long Term Equity.  Have been doing
this fund for 8 years.
₹5 lakh has been collected so far.
Stay in this fund or exit.  And secondly, it can
give such returns in the long term.  Their
education goal is
20 lakhs in 7 to 8 years.  What is your suggestion Pankaj
ji?  Look, no doubt the
performance of this fund has not been good for some time
but it happens with every fund
that sometimes there are some ups and downs
because a fund manager has his investment
style and at times that style does
not work which has happened with this fund also
but you will see if the
changes that have been made in the portfolio of the fund, I
hope that the fund will perform well in the coming time
so according to me you should stay
here because you will leave from here and
go somewhere else and later this fund will
start performing.  So if you are a long term
investor then according to me you should
not panic and should wait
with patience.  Definitely,
in the coming time you will be
able to see improvement in its performance.  This can be expected.
Ok.  So here are some suggestions regarding your funds.
Now let us quickly ask Pankaj ji about the top up of funds.
Pankaj ji, please tell me the top of
funds with which portfolio creation can be done.
Absolutely, if you are a long term
investor and are thinking accordingly
because if we are talking about equity
and there is a lot of volatility in the market then the
perspective should be very long term.  So
in such a situation, you should include ICICI Protial
Asset Allocation Multi Asset Fund, which is
basically an asset allocation fund that
invests in all three – equity, debt and commodity.
Along with this, you can also include Aditya Birla Sun Life
Nifty 50 Index Fund
in your portfolio.  This
is an index fund.  Motilal Oswal Mid Cap
Fund as well as Canara Rubeco
Small Cap Fund in small caps.  But keep in mind that these funds will be
suitable for your long term investment goals.  If you are
looking to invest for a very short term, then it would be
better to go for debt funds.
Ok.  So it's time to
create a portfolio accordingly, but for the long
term, you can create this portfolio
with these four funds,
which include Pro Multi Asset Fund, Aditya
Birla's Nifty 50 Index Fund,
Mutual Cap and Croboco Salc Cap.
Create your portfolio with these funds. Rest, there is Money to
help you at every step.
Thank you Pankaj ji for coming to the show, for
giving your views on all the queries, as well as for
sharing details with our viewers about health insurance. That's all for
Yum Money,
but the news continues on CNBC Awaaz.
Namaskar
Tumhi
[Music]